

#### **CONTACT ME**

- +62 898-3863-501
- hanss9966@gmail.com
- Taman Cibinong Asri Block C2 No. 9B, Cibinong, Bogor Regency, West Java, Indonesia

### **EDUCATION**

- Akademi Kulineri De Chef 2022 - 2023
- SMA Negeri 3 Cibinong **Natural Science Major** 2018 - 2021

# M Raihan

# Commis Chef

#### **SUMMARY**

Hard working and motivated commis chef, have passion for foods and cooking skills with 1 years of professional experience assisting chefs with food preparation processes and various kitchen duties according to food safety and hygiene regulations. Takes direction well and can work with team under pressure while maintaining a positive attitude.

#### **CERTIFICATE**

 Diploma Awards "Westren Seafood Main Course With 2023 Pasta" at 5Th SIAL INTERFOOD 2023 • Certificate of Competence Food & Beverage Product

2023

Trainee Certificate Royal Safari Garden

2023

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Jr. Cook 2024 - Present

Remboelan

- Make an Order
- Ensure that the dishes made are up to standard
- Prepare all condiment
- Report stock opname section

Cook 2023 - 2024

### **Beau Bakery**

- Make an Order
- Ensure that the dishes made are up to standard
- Help CDP and Sous Chef create dishes for special events
- Help Cook helper to prepare something

#### Trainee as Garde Manger and Cook

2023

#### Royal Safari Garden I Indonesia

- · Prepare all the ingredients such as vegetables, fruits, and spices
- Prepare an order such as pasta, pizza, and steak
- Maintain the kitchen cleanliness
- In charge for the inventory stock check

Live Streamer 2023

#### Indonesia

Ever participated in a Live cooking event to make Basil Pasta Dough and was covered by several local media

#### **SKILLS**

Stronger in Indonesian Cuisine	9/10
· · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · · ·	7/10
<ul> <li>Mastering the use of different types of knives</li> </ul>	7/10
<ul> <li>Skilled in the use of machine kitchen tools</li> </ul>	8/10
<ul> <li>Knows most of Indonesian Cuisine's</li> </ul>	8/10
<ul> <li>High creativity to experiment in making dishes</li> </ul>	9/10



	v		٥	•	`	1	0	n	u	n	•	`	·	3 2		ļ	1		Z	
Average Point	(Kejujuran )	Honesty	( Tanggung Jawab )	Responsibility	( Disiplin )	Discipline	( Kerjasama )	Team Work	(Inisiatif)	Initiative	(Kompetensi Dasar & Tambahan)	Penguasaan Kompetensi	( Kesopanan & Komunikasi )	Courtesy & Communication	( Kehadiran )	Attendance	( Kelengkapan )	Grooming	rescription	
at																			1	
																			2	
																		۷.	3	Score
		<				<				<		<				<			4	
				<				<						<					5	
4.2		4		5		4		5		4		4		5		4		u	TOTAL POINT	Total Boint

Remarks

A = 5 B = 4 C = 3 D = 2 E = 1

: Exellent : Good : Average : Poor : Very Poor



# **CERTIFICATE**

OF PARTICIPATION

THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT

M Raihan

HAS PARTICIPATED IN

San Remo
Western Seafood Main Course with Pasta

THE 5TH LACUISINE COMPETITION 2023

HELD IN CONJUNCTION WITH

SIAL InterFOOD

SIAL Interfood Jakarta 8th-14th November 2023 JIEXPO - Kemayoran Jakarta, Indonesia

Rafael Triloko Basanto

ENDORSED BY



ORGANIZED BY





Michael Strautmanis

Chief Judge of The 5th LaCuisine 202



# CERTIFICATE

OF AWARD

THIS IS TO CERTIFY THAT

M Raihan

WAS AWARDED WITH DIPLOMA

SAN REMO – Western Seafood

Main Course with Pasta

THE 5TH LACUISINE COMPETITION 2023

HELD IN CONJUNCTION WITH

SIAL

SIAL Interfood Jakarta 8th-11th November 2023 JIEXPO - Kemayoran Jakarta, Indonesia

The

Rafael Triloko Basanto Chairman of The 5th LaCuisine 2023 Michael Strautmanis
Chief Judge of The 5th LaCuisine 2023

ENDORSED BY













SERTIFIKASI PROFESI INDONESIAN PROFESSIONAL **CERTIFICATION AUTHORITY** 

### SERTIFIKAT KOMPETENSI CERTIFICATE OF COMPETENCE

No. 5511 5120 2 0017973 2023

Dengan ini menyatakan bahwa, This is to certify that,

#### M RAIHAN

No. Reg. PAR.1302.03848.2023

Telah kompeten pada bidang: Is competent in the area of:

Pengolahan Makanan & Minuman Food & Beverages Production

Dengan kualifikasi / kompetensi: With qualification / competency:

Skema Sertifikasi level II - Bidang Tata Boga (Cookery) Kualifikasi Kerja Nasional Indonesia (KKNI)

National Occupational Certification Schemes Referencing to ACCSTP And CATC on Tourism Professional in the Area Food & Beverages Production (Cookery)

> Sertifikat ini berlaku untuk : 3 (tiga) tahun This certification is valid for : 3 (three) years

> > Depok, 17 Oktober 2023

Atas nama Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi On behalf of Indonesia Professional Certification Authority Lembaga Sertifikasi Profesi Rajawali Hospitality Nusantara Professional Certification Body Rajawali Hospitality Nusantara

Herlin Sulistyawati, SE. MM

(Director)



## Daftar Unit Kompetensi

List of Unit(s) of Competency

# Sertifikat II Bidang Tata Boga ( Food And Beverage Production - Cookery )

Kompetensi Umum & Inti ( General and Core Competencies )

NO	Kode Unit Kompetensi Code of Competency Unit	Judul Unit Kompetensi Title of Competency Unit								
1.	D1.HRS.CL1.02	Melaksanakan prosedur keselamatan makanan Apply standard safety procedures for handling foodstuffs								
2.	D1.HRS.CL1.03	Membersihkan lokasi / area dan peralatan Clean and maintain kitchen equipment and utensils								
3.	D1.HRS.CL1.04	Berkomunikasi secara efektif melalui telepon Communicate effectively on the telephone								
4.	D1.HRS.CL1.05	Mengikuti prosedur kebersihan di tempat kerja Comply with workplace hygiene procedures								
5.	D1.HRS.CL1.07	Menerapkan prosedur kesehatan, keselamatan dan keamanan kerja Implement occupational health and safety procedures								
6.	D1.HRS.CL1.08	Memelihara pengetahuan tentang industri perhotelan Maintain hospitality industry knowledge								
<b>'</b> .	D1.HRS.CL1.11	Melakukan prosedur administrasi  Aerform cierical procedures								
3.	D1.HRS.CL1.12	Melakukan prosedur dasar pertolongan pertama  Perform basic First Aid procedures  Menakan dan atau diagram								
).	D1.HRS.CL1.14	Membaca dan menerjemahkan instruksi dasar, arah dan atau diagram Read and interpret basic instructions, directions and/or diagrams								
.0.	D1.HRS.CL1.17	Berkomunikasi secara lisan dalam Bahasa Inggris pada tingkat operasional dasar Speak English at a basic operational level								
1.	D1.HRS.CL1.18	Bekerjasama secara efektif dengan kolega dan pelanggan Work effectively with colleagues and customers								
2.	D1.HRS.CL1.19	Bekerja dalam lingkungan sosial yang berbeda Work in a socially diverse environment								
3.	D1.HRS.CL1.20	Melakukan tugas perlindungan anak yang relevan dengan industri pariwisata Perform child protection duties relevant to the tourism industry								
ie	D1.HCC.CL2.01	Menggunakan metode dasar memasak Apply basic techniques of commercial cookery								
	D1.HCC.CL2.11	Menyiapkan dan menyimpan makanan secara aman dan higienis Prepare and store food in a safe and hygienic manner								
NGSIO	NAL									
Ţ	D1.HCC.CL2.01	Menggunakan metode dasar memasak Using basic cooking methods								
	D1.HCC.CL2.02	Membina dan menjaga kendali mutu dalam produksi makanan Fostering and maintaining quality control in food production								
	D1.HCC.CL2.03	Mengidentifikasi dan menyiapkan daging  Identifying and preparing meat								
	D1.HCC,CL2.04	Mempertahankan strategi penyimpanan yang aman dari makanan siap saj Maintaining a safe storage strategy of ready to eat food								
i	D1.HCC.CL2.11	Menyiapkan dan menyimpan makanan dengan cara yang aman dan Prepare and store food in a safe and clean manner								
	D1.HCC.CL2.12	Menyiapkan appetiser dan salad Preparing appetizers and salads								
	D1.HRS.CL1.01	Mencari dan mendapatkan data komputer Search and get computer data								
	D1.HRS.CL1.09	Menangani dan menyelesaikan situasi konflik Handle and resolve conflict situations								

OSPITAL NUSAN NUSA

M RAIHAN
Tanda tangan pemilik
Signature of holder

Depok, 17 Oktober 2023

Lembaga Sertifikasi Profesi Rajawali Hospitality Nusantara Professional Certifying Body for RAIN

> <u>Irfan Ariyandi</u> Manajer Sertifikasi

Manager of Certification

### PT. HARAPAN KULINER LESTARI

Jl. RS fatmawati No.14 B Cilandak Barat, Cilandak, Jakarta Selatan Kode Pos: 12420 No. Telp 021-27825463

# LETTER OF REFERENCE No.061/HKL-HR/LOR/V/2024

Jakarta, 06 May 2024

This certifies that Mr. M. Raihan has been working for PT. Harapan Kuliner Lestari (BEAU Bakery) since September 13<sup>rd</sup>, 2023 until May 13<sup>rd</sup>, 2024 as a Cook.

On behalf of the management, we want to say thank you for your ability and responsibility during the company.

We wish he all the very best in his career.

PT. Harapan Kuliner Lestari

PT. HARAPAN KULINER LESTARI

Salfida Fajrin

Human Resources & General Affair